Guide to the Carol Berger Chicago performing arts playbills collection, 1988-2015
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
Carol Berger Chicago performing arts playbills collection
1988-2015
C0263
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
1.0 linear feet (4 boxes)
This collection largely consists of playbills from Chicago's Lyric Opera House, the Chicago Symphony Orchestra, and regional theatres collected by Carol Berger. There are also ticket stubs from the performances, as well as materials from the Art Institute of Chicago.
Berger, Carol
Box 1
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Carol Berger in 2015.
Historical Information
The Lyric Opera of Chicago was founded by Carol Fox, Lawrence V. Kelly and Nicola Rescigno in 1954. It is located in the Civic Opera Building which first opened its doors on November 4, 1929. The Civic Opera Building was envisioned by Samuel Insull as the predominant place for operatic performances. The Lyric Opera is now globally renowned for their chorus, orchestra, as well as their preservation of the cultural importance of opera in Chicago, Illinois. Several other nationally and internationally renowned theatres are also included in the collection of playbills.
Scope and Content note
This collection largely consists of playbills from Chicago's Lyric Opera House, the Chicago Symphony Orchestra, and regional theatres collected by Carol Berger. There are also ticket stubs from a handful of the performances, as well as materials from the Art Institute of Chicago. The playbills from Chicago's Lyric Opera House span the course of twenty-one seasons from the 34th to the 57th. The largest part of the collection consists of playbills from regional theatres from across the United States, including one piece from the San Francisco Opera. A smaller portion of the collection is made up of pamphlets from the Art Institute of Chicago that describe a few fashion and art exhibitions from 1996 to 2015.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged by venue, followed by format. The playbills are arranged chronologically by season, and alphabetically within each season.
Bibliography
Related Material
Special Collections Research Center holds many other performing arts collections which include the, the, the, and the.
Index Terms
Geographical Names:
Chicago (Ill.)
Subjects:
Performing arts.; Theater programs.; Theater--United States.; Theater.
Contents List
- Lyric Opera: 57th Season, 2011 - 2012 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Lyric Opera: 54th Season, 2008 - 2009 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Lyric Opera: 53rd Season, 2007 - 2008 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Lyric Opera: 52nd Season, 2006 - 2007 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Lyric Opera: 51st Season, 2005 - 2006 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Lyric Opera: 50th Season, 2004 - 2005 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Lyric Opera: 49th Season, 2003 - 2004 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Lyric Opera: 48th Season, 2002 - 2003 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Lyric Opera: 47th Season, 2001 - 2002 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Lyric Opera: 46th Season, 2000 - 2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Lyric Opera: 45th Season, 1999 - 2000 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Lyric Opera: 44th Season, 1998 - 1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Lyric Opera: 43rd Season, 1997 - 1998 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Lyric Opera: 42nd Season, 1996 - 1997 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Lyric Opera: 41st Season, 1995 - 1996 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Lyric Opera: 40th Season, 1994 - 1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Lyric Opera: 39th Season, 1993 - 1994 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Lyric Opera: 38th Season, 1992 - 1993 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Lyric Opera: 36th Season, Nuveen Radio Broadcast Guide, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Lyric Opera: 35th Season, 1989 - 1990 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Lyric Opera: 34th Season, 1988 - 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Lyric Opera: Backstage Tours, March 2003, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Marshall Field's Day of Music, September 16, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Chicago Symphony Orchestra: The Morton Arboretum, June 27-30, 2013 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Symphony Center Special Concerts, 2003 - 2004 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Notebook: Chicago Symphony Orchestra, 1997 - 2008 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Symphony Center Presents, November 2013 - March 2015 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Chicago Symphony Orchestra: The Morton Arboretum, November 2013 - 2014 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Ravinia Magazine: Vol.8, No.6, July 28 - August 3, 2014 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Ravinia: Festival, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Ravinia: 'International Festival of the Arts' books, June 14, 1998 - June 1, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Playbill, 2002 - 2007 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Stagebills, 1989 - 1995 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Stagebills, 1996 - 2000 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- The Goodman Theatre, 2003 - 2004 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Chicagoplays, 2014 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- The MAC, 2002 - 2005 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Metropolitan Opera, 1996 - 1998 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Wheaton College Conservatory of Music, May 1, 2014 - February 21, 2015 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Chicago Shakespeare Theatre, 1999 - 2013 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Auditorium Theatre: Show Boat, April 1996 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Mercury Theater: Over the River and Through the Woods, August, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Navy Pier: Skyline Stage Program, July - October, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- The Art Institute of Chicago: Lucy McKenzie, October 23, 2014 - January 18, 2015 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- The Art Institute of Chicago: Passion for Fashion, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- The Art Institute of Chicago: Visitor Guide, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- The Art Institute of Chicago: Cezanne to Picasso, February 17 - May 12, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- The Art Institute of Chicago: Exhibition Guide, September 30, 1996 - January 5th, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- The Tweaksters, October 20, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Cirque Du Soleil: Dralion, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Metamorphoses, October - November 2012 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Basically Bach, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- San Francisco Opera, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Lyric Opera: Tickets, November 5, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Northlight Theatre Tickets, October 10, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Oriental Theatre: Mama Mia Ticket, September 18, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Cadillac Palace Theatre: The Pirate Queen tickets, November 18, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Ravinia Concert Tickets, June 6th, July 27th, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- The Goodman Theatre: The White Snake ticket, May 8, 2014 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Symphony Center Tickets, June 27th, 2013 - March 16th, 2015 (Box 4, Folder 28)